An experience in terror and suspense.
The Fury is a horror, science fiction, thriller film directed by Brian De Palma.
When a devious plot separates CIA agent Peter Sandza from his son, Robin,
the distraught father manages to see through the ruse.
Taken because of his psychic abilities, Robin is being held by Ben Childress, who is studying
people with supernatural powers in hopes of developing their talents as weapons.
Soon Peter pairs up with Gillian, a teen who has
telekinesis, to find and rescue Robin.
Peter Sandza, played by Kirk Douglas.
Gillian Bellaver, played by Amy Irving.
Ben Childress, played by John Cassavetes.
Hester, played by Carrie Snodgress.
Dr. Jim McKeever, played by Charles Durning.
Robin Sandza, played by Andrew Stevens.
The Fury is a 1978 American neo-noir supernatural horror thriller film directed by Brian De Palma and starring
Kirk Douglas, John Cassavetes, Amy Irving, Carrie Snodgress, Charles Durning, and Andrew Stevens.
Its plot follows a former CIA agent (Douglas) who uses a young teenager with psychic powers (Irving) to help locate his
missing telekinetic son (Stevens) who has been abducted by an agent (Cassavetes) of a secret government agency.
The screenplay by John Farris was based on his 1976 novel of the same name.
Produced by Frank Yablans and released by 20th Century Fox on March 15, 1978, the film was both
critically and commercially successful, grossing $24 million from a $7.5 million budget.
Film critic Pauline Kael highly lauded the music, composed and conducted by John Williams,
calling it "as apt and delicately varied a score as any horror movie has ever had".
The film explores themes of hotel, beach, middle east, based
on novel or book, parent child relationship.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.